Shawn McCrum

Computer Technician, IT, Web Developer, CRU Supervisor

I have always had a fascination with technology. As a child I built my own computer. While attending High School I worked at a local computer shop. I acquired a base knowledge not only computers, but, customer service, and business ethics too. While attending college I used my skills to team-up with a like-minded friend to start a business. We accepted job varying in difficulty; testing our skill while also giving us first-hand experience interacting with clients. Mainly we would create and maintain websites and social media accounts for our clients. Occasionally, we accepted jobs: installing security cameras, repairing computers / laptops, and installing sound systems. Continue reading my resume for the rest of the story.



Personal Info

Experience

Address

Zephyr St.

Arvada, CO, 80004

Phone : (201) 956-5546

E-mail : xmccrum@gmail.com

GitHub : https://bit.ly/2WRI289
LinkedIn : https://bit.ly/39cb7Ol



Front End:

HTML, HRML5, CSS, JS, WordPress

Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects

Browser developer tools (F12), xPath, API

SEO best practices

Social media management

Back End:

Python, Django

PHP

MySQL, SQL

Scalability, Server Architecture, Data

Transformation

Mentionable Skills:

NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, NLTK, Selenium, Pytest, Multi-Threading, Agile, Jenkins, Maven, AWS, Quantopian, Functional testing, Path Testing, Stress Testing, black box, white box, happy path

IT Skills:

Camera, speakers, wire installation

Personality:

Reliable, organized, team player, determined, confident, always learning

2019-04 -

CRU Supervisor

2019-06

PanurgyOEM

- Learn job operations of each member of my team
- Delegate work
- Cross trained team members
- Measure individual/group efficiency
- Optimize production
- Meet deadlines

2016-12 -2018-04

Computer Technician

Advantage Computers & Network Solutions || Cross Technology

- Setting up hardware, installing, and configure software and drivers
- Maintaining and repairing technological equipment
- Diagnose hardware / software related issues
- Troubleshoot both in person and over the phone
- Disassemble / reassemble computers, laptops, peripheral device, ect
- Virus scans, HDD testing, data transfer, repairing / installing Windows, Apple, and Linux environments

2015-06 -

Web Developer

2016-11 Centis Technology

- Use a combination of markup languages to write web pages
- Social media and website maintenance
- Assist back-end developers
- Create quality mockups and prototypes on tight timelines
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Management and organization of multiple websites
- Stay up-to-date on emerging technologies

2011-11

Co-CEO

Point-Mass

- Front-end / Back-end development
- Finding new clients and meeting with them to discuss their needs
- Staying up-to-date on industry standards
- Create and maintain social media accounts for clients
- Create and maintain website content and SEO
- Communicate daily with my team to discuss each days agenda

Projects & Experience

Personal

- Created automation script to trade cryptocurrency using an API
- Created a back testing tool to perform technical analysis with multiple stocks
- Automated sentiment analysis of news articles to determine market impact
- Built several web crawlers, GUI, and tests
- Built a mining rig with 6 GPU's

Education

2008-09 - Fair Lawn High School

2011-06 • 3.4 GPA

Completed general education

2016-09 - Bergen Community College2020-01 • Computer Science major